Privacy Policy
==============

**Effective Date: 16/10/24**

Welcome, and thank you for your interest in Medito ("Medito", "we", or "us"). This Privacy Policy (the "Policy") explains how Stichting Medito and its affiliates and subsidiaries collect, use, and disclose Personal Information in the context of the Medito mobile app (the "App"), our website at www.meditofoundation.org (the "Website"), our online community platforms, and other services (collectively, the "Services"). This Policy also describes your rights and choices with respect to your personal information, and how you can contact us if you have any questions or concerns.

1\. Personal Information We Collect
-----------------------------------

We may collect Personal Information about you directly from you, from third parties, or automatically through your use of the Services. In this Policy, "Personal Information" means any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual.

### Information Provided by You

* **Contact information:** When you contact us, sign up for our newsletter, or register with the Services, you may provide us with contact information, such as your name and email address.
* **Correspondence and feedback:** When you contact us via a contact form, email, survey, through the App, or by other means, you provide us with your contact information and the contents and nature of your correspondence or survey responses.
* **Contributions:** When you volunteer with or otherwise contribute to Medito, you may provide us with contributor information, such as the code, documentation or other material you contribute, the time and date of your contributions, your username and profile information, and any related comments and discussions.

### Information Collected via Automated Means

#### For Both App and Website:

* **Device information:** When you use the Services, we automatically receive information about your device, including your IP address, device type, web browser, screen resolution, and operating system.
* **Coarse location information:** When you use the Services, we estimate your location at city/country level based on your IP address and browser language.

#### App-Specific:

* **App usage information:** We collect information about your use of the App, including the date, time, and duration of your sessions, the App version, what you tapped on, the content you accessed, what you listened to, and the route you took to navigate through the App. **Note:** This information is collected automatically when you use the App, even without an account. By using the App, you agree to this data collection.

#### Website-Specific:

* **Website usage information:** When you use the Website, we automatically receive information about your use of the Website, including the web pages that you visit just before or just after you use the Website, as well as information about your interactions with the Website, including the date, time and duration of your visit, where you clicked, and the route you took to navigate through the Website.
* **Cookie information:** We and third parties may automatically collect information about your visit to and use of the Website via cookies (see section 4 below for more information).

### Information Collected from Third Parties

* **Donation information:** When you donate to Medito, we receive your contact information and donation amount from our payment providers.
* **Social media information:** When you engage with Medito on social media, we may receive your profile information, posts, and other information from the social media platform.
* **Community platform information:** When you participate in our community platforms (such as WhatsApp or Telegram groups), we may collect information you provide in these communities, as well as information provided by the platform itself.

2\. How We Use Personal Information
-----------------------------------

We use your Personal Information for the following purposes:

* **Providing the Services:** We rely on vendors and service providers for the provision of our Services, such as cloud service providers and analytics providers.
* **Communicating with you:** We use your Personal Information as necessary to contact you for administrative purposes, including to provide information that you request, to respond to comments and questions, and to provide you with customer support.
* **Marketing:** If you have opted in, we use your email address and other Personal Information to send marketing communications, including updates on promotions and events relating to Medito and the Services. You can opt out of receiving promotional communications as described under section 6 below.
* **Processing donations:** We use your Personal Information as necessary to process your donation.
* **Understanding usage and improving the Services:** We have a legitimate interest to use your Personal Information to understand and analyze the usage trends and preferences of our users, to improve the Services, and to develop new products, services, features, and functionality.
* **Administrative and legal purposes:** We may be legally required or have a legitimate interest to use your Personal Information to address administrative or legal issues pertaining to Medito, including to enforcing our contracts, complying with legal obligations, and defending against legal claims or disputes.

3\. When We Disclose Personal Information
-----------------------------------------

We disclose Personal Information about you to the following recipients and in the following circumstances:

* **Vendors and service providers:** We rely on vendors and service providers for the provision of our Services, such as cloud service providers, customer support service providers and analytics providers.
* **Payment processors:** We disclose your information to payment processors in order to receive payment for the use of our Platform, such as Stripe.
* **Legal:** Information about our users, including Personal Information, will be disclosed to law enforcement agencies, regulatory bodies, public authorities or pursuant to the exercise of legal proceedings if we are legally required to do so, or if we believe, in good faith, that such disclosure is necessary to comply with a legal obligation or request, to enforce our terms and conditions, to prevent or resolve security or technical issues, or to protect the rights, property or safety of Medito, our users, a third party, or the public.
* **Medito group:** We may disclose personal information about you to our affiliates and subsidiaries.
* **Change of corporate ownership:** If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, reorganization, partnership, asset sale or other transaction, we may disclose your Personal Information as part of that transaction.
* **Researchers:** We may share your data with researchers only if you have agreed to it by registering to a research project/study.

4\. How We Use Cookies and Similar Technologies
-----------------------------------------------

Cookies are small pieces of data that may be stored in and retrieved from your web browser while you browse a website. In this Policy, cookies and similar storage technologies, such as JavaScript localStorage, are collectively referred to as "cookies".

Our Website uses cookies to collect information about your browsing activities and to distinguish you from other users of our Website. This aids your experience when you browse our Website and also allows us to improve the functionality of our Website.

We use the following cookies:

* **Strictly necessary cookies:** Some cookies are strictly necessary to make our Website available to you; for example, to provide login functionality and for user authentication and security. We cannot provide you with the Website without this type of cookie.
* **Functional cookies:** These are used to recognise you when you return to our Website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your account preferences.
* **Analytical or performance cookies:** We also use cookies for analytics purposes in order to operate, maintain, and improve our Website. We use third party analytics providers, including Google Analytics, to help us understand how users engage with the Services. Google Analytics uses first-party cookies to track user interactions which helps show how users use our Services. This information is used to compile reports and to help us improve our Services. The reports disclose Website trends without identifying individual visitors. You can opt out of Google Analytics without affecting how you visit our Website by going to tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout or via Google's Ads settings.

You can block cookies by setting your internet browser to block some or all or cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our Website.

Except for essential cookies, all cookies will expire after 12 months.

5\. How Long We Retain Personal Information
-------------------------------------------

Medito stores all Personal Information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes set out in this Policy, or for as long as we are required to do so by law or in order to comply with a regulatory obligation. When deleting Personal Information, we will take measures to render such Personal Information irrecoverable or irreproducible, and the electronic files which contain Personal Information will be permanently deleted.

6\. Your Rights and Choices
---------------------------

In certain circumstances, you have the following rights in relation to your Personal Information that we hold:

* **Access:** You have the right to access the Personal Information we hold about you, and to receive an explanation of how we use it and who we share it with.
* **Correction:** You have the right to correct any Personal Information we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete.
* **Erasure:** You have the right to request for your Personal Information to be erased or deleted.
* **Object to processing:** You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Information where we are relying on a legitimate interest or if we are processing your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes.
* **Restrict processing:** You have a right in certain circumstances to stop us processing your Personal Information other than for storage purposes.
* **Portability:** You have the right to receive, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, Personal Information that you have provided to us if we process it on the basis of our contract with you, or with your consent, or to request that we transfer such Personal Information to a third party.

Please note that, prior to any response to the exercise of such rights, we may need to verify your identity. In addition, we may have valid legal reasons to refuse your request, and will inform you if that is the case. You always have the right to file a complaint with the national data protection authority, but we hope that you contact us first so we can address your concerns. For more information, or to exercise your rights, please contact us at the contact details below.

7\. International Visitors
--------------------------

We may transfer your Personal Information outside of the European Economic Area. When we do so, we shall ensure that relevant safeguards are in place to afford adequate protection for your Personal Information. Further details regarding the relevant safeguards can be obtained from us on request.

8\. Children's Privacy
----------------------

Our Services are not directed to children, and we do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use Personal Information from children under the age of 16. If you learn that a child has provided us with Personal Information in violation of this Policy, please contact us as indicated below.

9\. Information Security
------------------------

We use certain physical, managerial, and technical safeguards that are designed to improve the integrity and security of Personal Information that we collect and maintain. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk.

10\. Changes to this Policy
---------------------------

We will notify you of any material changes so that you have time to review the changes.

11\. Contact us
---------------

Please contact us with any questions or comments about this Policy, your Personal Information, our use and disclosure practices, or your consent choices by email at [\[email protected\]](https://meditofoundation.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or by postal mail at:

Stichting Medito  
Attn: Privacy  
Bogortuin 203  
1019 PE Amsterdam  
Netherlands

12\. App-Specific Information
-----------------------------

* **No Account Required:** You can use the App without creating an account. However, by using the App, you agree to the collection and use of your information as described in this Policy.
* **Automatic Data Collection:** The App automatically collects usage, device, and location information as described in Section 1. There is no way to opt out of this data collection while using the App.
* **Push Notifications:** We may send push notifications to your device. You can manage these in your device settings.
* **Offline Use:** Some features of the App may be available offline. We will sync data collected offline when you reconnect to the internet.

13\. Website-Specific Information
---------------------------------

* **Cookies:** The Website uses cookies as described in Section 4. You can manage your cookie preferences through your browser settings.
* **Newsletter:** If you sign up for our newsletter on the Website, we will use your email address to send you updates about Medito. You can unsubscribe at any time using the link provided in each email.
* **Donations:** When you make a donation through our Website, we collect and process the necessary information to complete the transaction.

14\. Community Platforms
------------------------

Medito maintains community spaces on various platforms, including but not limited to WhatsApp and Telegram. When you join and participate in these communities:

* **Information Collection:** We may collect information that you provide in these communities, as well as information provided by the platform itself (such as your username, profile picture, or activity status).
* **Platform Policies:** Your use of these platforms is also subject to the respective privacy policies and terms of service of WhatsApp, Telegram, or any other platform we may use in the future.
* **Linking Information:** If you choose to link your community profile with your Medito app account, we may associate the information from these platforms with your app usage data. This allows us to provide a more personalized experience and improve our services.
* **Data Usage:** Information collected from community platforms may be used to understand user preferences, improve our services, and communicate important updates or offers.
* **Opting Out:** You can choose to leave our community groups at any time. However, please note that some information may have already been collected and associated with your account.

15\. Research Participation
---------------------------

If you choose to participate in research studies:

* You will be asked for explicit consent before any research-specific data collection begins.
* The types of data collected and how they will be used will be explained in the specific research consent form.
* You can withdraw from a study at any time.
* Data shared with researchers will be anonymized or pseudonymized to protect your privacy.

For more information about our research practices, please contact us.

16\. Data Linking and Integration
---------------------------------

* **Account Linking:** If you choose to create an account in the Medito app, we may offer the option to link this account with your profiles on our community platforms (such as WhatsApp or Telegram groups).
* **Data Integration:** When accounts are linked, we may integrate data from different sources (app usage, community participation, etc.) to create a more comprehensive user profile. This helps us to:
* Provide more personalized content and recommendations
* Improve our services based on a better understanding of user behavior across platforms
* Facilitate seamless experiences between the app and community spaces
* **Control Over Linking:** You have control over whether to link your accounts. You can also unlink them at any time through your app settings or by contacting us.
* **Data Separation:** If you choose not to link accounts or to unlink them, we will maintain separate data sets for your app usage and community participation.

17\. Updates to This Policy
---------------------------

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in our practices or for other operational, legal, or regulatory reasons. We will notify you of any material changes through the App, Website, or community platforms, as appropriate.

Unless otherwise indicated, Stichting Medito is the entity responsible or "data controller" for the processing of Personal Information described in this Policy.

#### Navigate

#### The Medito app

#### Foundation

Medito Foundation or in Dutch, Medito Stichting / Stichting Medito  
Non-profit organisation registered in the Netherlands 🇳🇱  
[\[email protected\]](https://meditofoundation.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) - KvK-nummer: 75284251 - RSIN: 860222627
